### Josh Anaba

Lagos, Nigeria 2349058294199 anabajoshchi@gmail.com

I am an enthusiastic software engineer with 2+ years of experience in building software, eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail, and excellent organizational skills. I thrive on building software applications that surpass users' expectations. Motivated to learn, keep growing, and excel in software engineering.

With frontend development as my focus and Javascript as my proficient tool, my experiences have been centered around working on products, small to large scale which have grown businesses efficaciously.

#### Technical Skills

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Vue.js
- React.js/ React Native
- Nuxt.js
- CSS, SASS & TailwindCSS

# Experience

JUNE 2021 - PRESENT

## **Acumen Digital, Lagos, Nigeria** - Software Developer (Full time)

- Building and maintaining functional & user-friendly applications using standard technologies which are fully integrated with APIs.
- Building and contributing to projects most of which fall under fintech, legal-tech, and e-commerce.
- I have been outsourced to work on contracts for local and foreign-based companies.
- Spearheading frontend projects from its foundation to finish.
- Collaborating with the team to build and maintain a chat API with pluggable SDKs.
- Rendering help to fellow software developers, and developer interns where needed.

AUGUST 2021 - MARCH 2022

#### **BeKinly, USA** - Software Developer (Contract)

Collaborated with the team in planning out and converting design ideas into a financial tech
application, which has really helped the black-americans and racially affected groups have
easier access to funds.

#### **Acumen Digital, Lagos, Nigeria** - Software Developer Intern

- I collaborated with the team in planning out and building a web application that utilized Google's Embedded Map, Direction & Geolocation APIs to track, update and provide directions to a client's map location.
- I worked with senior engineers to build an online marketplace application that helps professionals find jobs, communicate with clients, and get paid.
- I built responsive and functional web applications using standard web technologies which are fully integrated with APIs.
- I learned the fundamentals of working with a team to plan out, build and deploy fully functional web applications where we worked with version control, and tools like Asana, Jira, and Github for collaboration.
- I worked with senior engineers and delivered tasks on time and which helped in honing my skill.

# **Education**

2018 - 2022

Olusegun Agagu University of Sci. and Tech, Ondo, Nigeria - Electrical and Electronics Engineering

# **Interests**

- -Software Engineering
- -loT
- -Art